# LOGARAJ RAMACHANDRAN

36, JLN PULAI 76, TAMAN PULAI UTAMA, 81300 SKUDAI, JOHOR, MALAYSIA. T | 60193014773 E | logaraj\_15@hotmail.com DOB | 15 JUN 1985



### **PERSONAL PROFILE**

I am a keen Engineering graduate whose skills has been developed throughout course of my degree, core skills include team building projects, leading people in a group, distributing the work load structure, working at set deadlines which enabled me to improve time management, having effective communication between team members.

#### **EDUCATION**

2009 – 2012 University of Hertfordshire, United Kingdom

BSc (Hons) Automotive engineering in Motorsport Technology Degree class: First Class Honors

Subject studies included: Automotive chassis & powertrain technology, automotive electrical system, simulation & Analysis techniques, Aerodynamic and engine design for motorsport, instrumentation and control system, racing body engineering, engineering operation and engineering science.

Final Year Project: Develop digital PID controller for the engine dynamometer – Use digital PID controller to stabilize a system with an existence of time delay. This design also used to reduce error in the engine dynamometer plant.

2008 Institute of Motor Industry (IMI), Malaysia

Diploma in vehicle maintenance and repair light vehicle (IMI Awards)

2003 – 2005 Malaysian France Institute, Malaysia

Diploma in engineering technology in Automotive Maintenance

Gain broad understanding of the interaction between automotive technology activities and engineering aspects to underlying theoretical concepts in the automotive engineering application.

Final Year Project: Electrical car seat – Design, test and build a model of electric car seat for the purpose of training for the future student.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2013 Mar – October Honda Malaysia Sdn.Bhd

Engine Technical Engineer

2009 - 2012 Brake & Service World Dealership, United Kingdom

Technician & Service consultant

Troubleshoot and maintenance continental vehicles (Bmw, VW, Audi,

Merc & Porche) and deal with customers problem.

2006 – 2009 BMW Malaysia (Auto Bavaria), Malaysia

Diagnostic technician & Service advisor

Performed minor and major BMW diagnosis and programming and promoted to service advisor to deal with customer's problem.

## TRAINING ATTENDED

2009 - 2012 MIG welding and gas cutter level one and two

Wheel alignment training for Porches

Air conditioning training Run flat tire training

Snap-on diagnostic training Workshop management training

2006 – 2009 BMW apprentice training level one and two

BMW new generation engine

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Engineering Application**

• Catia modelling software V5 release 18

- National Instrumentation lap view software version 8.6
- Phoenix wind tunnel design and simulation software
- Ansys12
- Pi toolbox software

#### Others

- Microsoft office (word, excel, power point and access)
- I am an enthusiastic team player with good communication skills. Motivated and keen to learn and explore new fields if given the opportunity.

# **MEMBERSHIP**

- Institute of Engineering technology (IET member)
- Institute of Motor Industry (IMIAL level 3 member)

#### **DETAILS**

Reason for leaving: Pursing studies in UK (past employment)

: Looking for career prospect in Singapore (current employment)

• Availability: Immediate

#### **REFEREES**

United Kingdom.

Mr. Trevor Webber Director, Brake and Service World dealership, Commerce House, 9a Chaul End Lane, Luton LU4 8EZ, Bedfordshire, Mr. Muthuramu Head of After Sales Auto Bavaria, JB Bangunan Star, Batu 4 ½, Jalan Skudai, 81200 Johor Bahru, Johor, Malaysia Mr. Vela Manager, Honda Malaysia Sdn, Bhd Hicom Industrial park Pegoh, 78000 Alor Gajah, Melaka,

Malaysia.

T | 01582562272 M | 0193431992

E | info@brakeandserviceworld.co.uk

M | 0126327461